Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
S-Superficial?
ひょ…表在性？
In other words, chilblains.
いわゆる霜焼け
You were close to getting frostbite.
もう少しで　凍傷になるところだったわね
If you walk around in a blizzard for
a long time with an automail like that,
こんな機械鎧で長時間吹雪の中歩いたら
接続部分の肉が凍傷になるのよ
you'll get frostbite where it is connected to your body.
You also won't be able to move very well unless you change your oil.
潤滑油も変えなきゃ　動きが鈍るし
Is that Buccaneer guy's automail made differently?
バッカニアとかいうヤツの機械鎧は違うのか
It's no good, Doc. I can't get this helmet off.
だめだ　先生
この頭絡まって取れん
Hey! That's my head!
あっ　僕の頭
All automail here must be made to be flexible, lightweight, and resistant to cold.
ここの機械鎧はね　柔軟性と軽量性
加えて　寒さに強いものでなくてはならないの
So through trial and error, an automail made with duralumin, carbon fiber, nickel, and copper was developed.
試行錯誤の結果生み出されたのが
ジュラルミン　炭素繊維
ニッケル　銅などを組み合わせた機械鎧
かぁ　普通に鉄だと思ってた
I thought it was just made of iron.
No wonder I couldn't destroy it.
どうりで破壊できねぇはずだ
おい先生
Hey Doc, you're not planning on spilling all the beans, are you?
何もかも話しちまうつもりじゃねぇだろうな
Why, what's wrong?
あらいいじゃない
He's a famous State Alchemist.
こちら天下の国家錬金術師よ
Are you sure he's real?
本物か
He has the silver pocketwatch.
銀時計持ってるって
A guy like this is of equal standing to a major?
こんなのが少佐相当官
If you're planning on staying up north for a while, you should switch to a cold climate automail.
北に長くいるつもりなら
寒冷地仕様の機械鎧へ付け替えなさい
Where does your automail mechanic work?
専属の技師は
Rush Valley.
ラッシュバレーにいるよ
They knew a customer was heading up north and didn't even bother to tell you the dangers or offer a replacement?
客が北国に来るってのに
説明も付け替えもなし
Well... I didn't tell her that I was going to be up here.
ああいや　北に来るって話してなかったから
If you don't want to die, you need to get it replaced;
even if it means your mechanic has to take a trip here.
死にたくなければ
出張してでも付け替えてもらうことね
Fine.
へい
That'll be 100 cenz for the coffee.
コーヒー代１００センズ
What a cheap trick...
汚ぇ
And this coffee tastes worse than the one at Eastern Headquarters.
東方司令部のよりまずいし
Your fault for letting your guard down.
油断する方が悪いのよ
So? What did you come here to do with that normal automail of yours?
で　そんなノーマル機械鎧で
何しにここへ来たんだ
Coming along without even passing through Headquarters.
司令部も通さず　単身で
That's right!
そうだ
We came here with a letter of introduction to see if Major General Armstrong could help us out,
アームストロング少将に力を借りようと
紹介状持ってきたのに
but that general didn't even listen to me and was
blabbering on about how she'd pluck my antenna off...
あの女将軍　人の話も聞かんで
オレのアンテナをむしるだなどと
Did you call, little brat?
呼んだか　赤チビ
"L-Little"...
あっ　赤
What is it?
なんだ　文句があるならさっさと言え
If you've got something to say, just say it.
M-My hair...
毛　毛が
I look ridiculous...
かっちょ悪い
So... I hear you're on good terms with my little brother, Alex.
さて
お前たち　弟のアレックスと親しくしていると聞いた
Is he doing well?
ヤツは元気か
あっ　ああ
Yeah.
As muscular as always.
相変わらず筋肉もりもり
He's as cheerful as can be.
元気いっぱいですよ
ちっ
"Tch"?!
Nevermind that.
まあいい
Moving right along, tell me why you came to see me without going through Headquarters first.
それより
司令部も通さず私に会いに来た理由を聞かせろ
Don't forget to include why that armor is empty, as well.
その鎧が空っぽな理由も包み隠さずすべてだ
It's actually... something I don't want a lot of people to know about.
なるべく　人に聞かれたくない話なんだけど
You've got nothing to worry about.
気にすることないわよ
Most of the people here have circumstances of their own.
ここのメンツは訳ありが多いもの
It's not uncommon for us to have things we don't want others to hear, as well.
人に聞かれたくない話なんて　珍しくもないわね
It's the kind of thing that could get me
court-martialed if people were to find out...
でも　知られたら軍法会議ものの話とかあるんだけど
I've done things of that caliber, as well.
それくらいのことは私もやっている
Brother, listen.
兄さん　ちょっと
I don't think she'll forgive us unless we tell her something.
話さないと許してくれないと思うよ
でも　ウィンリィが人質なんだ
But Winry is practically a hostage.
I have an idea.
あっ よし
Let's leave out the part about the
Führer President and the Homunculi.
大総統や人造人間のことは　言わない方向でいこう
What are you whispering on about?!
何を話してる
I don't have all day!
さっさとせんか
Then I guess we can just tell her,
"We're on a journey to get our bodies back".
じゃあ　あくまで元の体に戻るための旅ってことで
I see. So that's why you're looking for a girl who carries this cat around.
なるほど
それでこの白黒猫を連れた娘を捜しているのか
うんうん
I get it now.
よく分かった
Then will you help us-
じゃあ協力してくれる
I get you are scatterbrains who act without thinking and end up adding fuel to flames because of your carelessness.
貴様らが　深く物事を考えず
うかつな行動で騒ぎを広げる
粗忽者であることは分かった
I don't want to keep fools like you in my castle.
そんな者を私の城に置きたくない
Seriously... why don't the higher-ups at Central keep fools like you chained up?
まったく
中央のヤツらはなぜこんなのを野放しにしておくのか
Leave here at once!
さっさと出ていけ
...is what I'd like to say, but I'm highly interested in Eastern Alchemy.
と言いたいところだが
錬丹術には興味がある
You two are acquainted with that girl from Xing, right?
貴様ら　その錬丹術の娘とは知り合いなのだな
Yeah, I guess you could say that...
ええ　まあ
It's technology we don't have in this country.
この国にはない技術だ　欲しい
I want it.
You can never have enough technology.
技術はいくらあってもいいものだ
Especially in this land, where we frequently combat Drakma, a large nation.
特に　ドラクマという大国と接しているこの地ではな
Depending on how we apply it, Eastern Alchemy may become a useful combat tool for us.
使い方によっては
錬丹術もよい武器になりそうだ
Hang on!
ちょっと待ってください
Eastern Alchemy is especially versed in medicinal purposes.
錬丹術は　医学に特化した技術ですよ
それを…
Using that for war-
やかましい
Did I give you permission to speak?
You're nothing but dogs that do nothing but bark within the borders of the country.
国の内側でキャンキャン吠えるだけの狗めが
Don't you forget for a second that you fools are living in peace because there exist those who protect the borders.
貴様らの生活の安寧は
国境を守る者あってこそだということを忘れるな
I am in charge of protecting the northern border.
北の国境線は私が引く
If the technique would be useful to my duty, then I'll take it. Whatever it may be.
その力になるなら　どんな技術でも頂く
Leave the search for the little girl to us.
錬丹術の娘捜しは我々に任せろ
I don't want you two out of the fortress.
貴様らは要塞を出るな
And Major Miles.
それとマイルズ少佐
Ma'am?
はっ
Give these two some work to do.
こいつらを働かせろ
W-What?!
"If a man will not work, he shall not eat."
働かざる者食うべからずだ
Can't argue with that...
ごもっとも
They've got quite a rough history behind them.
なかなかハードな経歴を持つヤツらですな
Although they seem to be fairly experienced in combat, I now know that they're just brats on the inside.
そこそこ修羅場慣れしていそうだが
中身はまだ甘ちゃんだということがよく分かった
Also...
それと　我々には話せない秘密があるということもな
It seems like they have some secrets they're not willing to share with us.
Hey, what are you going to make us do exactly?
なあ　仕事って何させられるんだよ
The doctor said that a lot of people here have
circumstances of their own. Does that go for you, too?
ここの連中は訳ありなのが多いって言ってたけど
あんたも何かあるのか
So you ask us about every detail of our lives,
and now you're ignoring us? Talk about unfair!
オレたちの秘密だけ根掘り葉掘り聞かれて
フェアじゃねぇよ
Do you really want to know?
知りたいか
Red eyes?!
赤い目
An Ishbalan?!
イシュヴァール人
Why...
なぜだ
I heard that all of the soldiers of Ishbalan descent were purged before the extermination...
イシュヴァール出身の軍人は
殲滅戦の前に粛清されたって
I do have some Ishbalan blood in me.
私には確かにイシュヴァール人の血が流れている
However, my grandmother, my father, and my wife do not.
だが　祖母　父
ちなみに妻も違う民族だ
The colors of my skin and eyes came from my grandfather.
この肌と目の色は　祖父の血が濃く出ている
Amestrian...
アメストリス人よ
You sure had your way with
the land of my ancestors, didn't you?
我が先祖の地イシュヴァールでは随分やってくれたな
You Ishbalans burned down my hometown, too, and even killed my friend's parents.
イシュヴァール人こそうちの田舎を焼いてくれたり
オレたちの幼なじみの両親をよくも殺してくれたな
Cut it out, Brother!
ちょっと　兄さん
Sorry about that.
すまない
You're actually the first one who talked back after I said that.
そういう切り返し方をしてきたヤツは
初めてだったからね
You were testing me, weren't you?
オレを試したな
I apologize.
いや　失礼
あの内乱の後
It's just that people view me with pity after that civil war.
やたら哀れみの目で見られることが多くてね
To be honest, I was getting sick of it.
正直　うんざりしてたんだ
But you were different.
だが君は違った
Well, I've met Ishbalans who wanted to kill me, ones who tried to kidnap me, and others I've made peace with.
まあ　イシュヴァール人には命狙われたり
誘拐されそうになったり　和解したり
濃ゆいおつきあいしてっからなぁ
So I've been through a lot.
And besides, I believe it's possible for individuals to be able to talk as equals without having to worry about race.
それに　人と人なら民族を超えて
対等に話し合えるはずだ
Were you enlisted in the military during the extermination, Major Miles?
マイルズ少佐は殲滅戦の時も軍に在籍してたのか
Yeah.
ああ　当時からアームストロング少将の補佐だった
I served as assistant to Major General Armstrong then, too.
The extermination began as soon as I was stationed here,
ここに赴任してすぐ殲滅戦が始まり
and all of my Ishbalan relatives, beginning with my grandfather, were killed in the East.
祖父をはじめイシュヴァール人の親族は
東の地で殺された
My life was saved due to my narrowly missing the requirements of the purge statute.
私は軍の粛清規約にわずかに外れていて助かった
Did you not come to despise the military?
軍を憎んだりしなかったのか
You don't hesitate to ask anything, do you?
君は本当になんでも聞くんだな
無知な自分がイヤなんだ
I hate being ignorant.
気に障ったんなら謝る
I apologize if I offended you in any way.
A State Alchemist being ignorant, huh...
国家錬金術師が無知ねぇ
I did despise what the military did.
軍のやったことは憎んだよ
And at the same time, I had doubts about the
Major General for keeping me as her assistant.
それと同時に
私を補佐として使い続けた少将に疑問を持った
By having someone like me, a person with Ishbalan blood around, it could cause trouble with the soldiers here.
イシュヴァールの血を引く私がいることで
ここにいる兵たちの間に波風が立つかもしれない
Yet, the Major General didn't exile me,
so I turned on her in anger and demanded answers.
だのになぜ追放しないのか
少将に食ってかかったことがある
Briggs shall not fall, no matter what happens.
ここブリッグズは　何があっても落とされてはならぬ地
Every soldier here must be strong and flexible, fulfilling my every command.
末端の兵一人一人が
主である私の意思の下
強く　かつ柔軟に　それでいて何事にも動じない
They must make up a sturdy army that would keep calm under all circumstances.
屈強な一軍であらねばならない
In other words, there's no time for racism.
つまり
差別などやってる暇はない
Because the blood of many races runs through your veins,
you view this country from many angles and with many values.
貴様の中に流れる多様な民族の血は
多様な価値観で
さまざまな角度からこの国を見ることができる
Because I was born and raised an Amestrian, I need someone like you by my side for me to be able to stand at the top.
生まれも育ちもアメストリス人である私が上に立つには
貴様のような者が必要だ
Follow my command without complaint, Miles!
四の五の言わずついてこい
マイルズ
Perfectly logical.
実に合理的　そしてごまかしのない言葉だった
Not to mention that her words carried no deception.
I proceeded to ask her, "Even then, what if the Ishbalan in me couldn't forgive the army and took over my mind?"
それでももし　私の中のイシュヴァール人の血が
国軍を許さぬと騒いだらどうするかと聞いたら
How do you think she responded to that?
少将はなんと言ったと思う
Very well. Bring it on.
よろしい　かかってこい
I'll accept a duel from you at any time, as a representative of the army.
国軍代表としていつでも決闘を受けてやる
Is what she said.
だとさ
うぇ　やな女
What an evil woman.
It should be easy saying that with a battalion at her back.
後ろに部隊を並べといて言うかよ
No, I'm fairly certain...
いや　あれはマジで
I'll slice you up in a one-on-one duel!
サシでぶった斬ってやる
...her eyes were saying that.
って目だったね
Are you aware of the universal law at this base?
ここの掟を知っているか
"Survival of the fittest", was it?
弱肉強食だっけ
That's right.
そうだ　力なき者は死に
Ones without power will die,
and ones with power will survive.
力ある者は生き残る
This is always true, under any circumstances.
２４時間３６５日変わることのない真理
It's very simple.
実にシンプルだ
There are no underlings, bosses, and no distinctions between race, ethnicities, and gender.
そこには下っ端もボスも
人種も民族も　男女の違いもない
There's a good example of the survival of the fittest concept.
これも弱肉強食
君が運が強い者だったから生き残った
You lived through it because you had good luck.
Looks like the guys who were supposed to be removing the icicles loafed on the job.
つらら落としのヤツらサボったな
It's your job now.
君たちの仕事だ
I'll tell one of my men to give you
a tour of the inside once you finish.
これが終わったら中を案内するよう
部下に言っておこう
I can't reach that high!
くそっ　届かん
あれっ　まさか
Huh? Don't tell me...
Warrant Officer Falman!
ファルマン准尉
Elric Brothers!
エルリック兄弟
What are you doing here?
なんでここにいるんだよ
Speak for yourself! I thought you were getting transferred to Northern Headquarters!
そっちこそ　北方司令部勤務じゃなかったっけ
I was actually sent here from Northern Headquarters.
いや　北方司令部から更にここに飛ばされてね
You were promoted to Second Lieutenant!
少尉になったんだ
Yeah.
ああ
Oh. Congratulations on your promot-
そっか　昇進おめで…
But why are you in charge of the icicles?
でもなんでつらら落とし
If you're here working the duties of the enlisted...
こんな超下っ端の仕事してるってことは
Looks like that'll be your last promotion.
出世コース外れたね
Shut up!
言うなっ
This is the development lair.
ここが開発層だ
おおっ　なんだこりゃ
Wow, what's that?
They're developing weapons using the best technology in the country under orders from Major General Armstrong.
アームストロング少将の意向でね
国内最先端の技術を集結して　兵器開発を行っている
Even automails for combat?
戦闘用の機械鎧も
Yes.
そう　次こっちね
Let me show you something else.
This is the lowest level of Briggs.
ここが　ブリッグズの最下層だ
It's really warm down here.
あったけぇな　上とは大違いだ
Totally different from how it is up at the top.
要塞内の生活ラインがここに集まっている
The lifeline of the fortress is gathered here.
Even if the top of the fortress is attacked,
the central part underground will remain unscathed.
要塞上部が攻撃されても
地下にあるこの心臓部は屁でもないのさ
Out of my way!
おら　邪魔だ　どけ
Don't be milling around!
フラフラ歩いてんなよ
ごめん
Sorry.
Hey Bobby, this way!
おいボビー　こっちだ
It's this pipe.
この管だ
This sound...
これ
It's coming from underground.
地下からだよ
What?!
何っ
It sounds like... someone's digging.
なんか岩を掘ってるような
Don't tell me the Drakmans are building
an underground passage beneath the fortress?!
まさかドラクマのヤツら　要塞の下に地下道を
It's really close!
近いぞ
What a drag...
めんどくせぇ
Really, what a drag...
ああ　めんどくせぇ
It's such a drag, I could die.
めんどくさくて　死にそうだ
But dying is also a drag.
けど　死ぬのもめんどくせぇ
ゾルフ·J·キンブリー
Solf J. Kimblee?
ここに来る貨物列車で重傷を負い
He was badly injured on a freight train on the way here and was hospitalized at the foot of the mountain.
ふもとの病院に収容されたそうです
He requests that Briggs supports him.
ブリッグズ支部で全面協力してくれと
Wasn't the Crimson Alchemist serving in jail?
紅蓮の錬金術師は受刑中ではなかったか
釈放されたそうです　大総統の命令で
Apparently, he was discharged.
Under orders from the Führer President.
気に入らんな
I don't like the sound of that.
What's the matter?!
何事だ
Intruders, ma'am! From underground!
侵入者あり　地下からです
What?!
何っ
Homunculus!
人造人間
Dammit!
くそっ
オレたちが人造人間に対抗する方法を探しに来たこと
So they knew we came up here to search for ways to fight against the Homunculi?!
お見通しかよ
寝るな
Don't fall asleep!!!
What?
ん　何
Well, you know.
えっ　いや　ほら
You heard about us from your Father at Central, right?
セントラルのお父様から話は聞いてんだろ
Y-Yeah.
そっ　そう
We just came here to search for ways to get our bodies back...
僕たちただ元の体に戻る方法を探しに来ただけで
Who... are you guys?
お前ら　誰
I... have to dig.
穴　掘る
What a drag...
めんどくせぇ
Such a drag...
ああ　めんどくせぇ
Wait, could it be that he...
こいつ　ひょっとして
Yeah. Maybe neither Father nor the
Führer President have told him about us yet.
お父様や大総統から　僕たちのこと聞いてないのかも
You bastard! So you are  spies from Drakma!
貴様　やはりドラクマの密偵だったのか
We're not!
誤解だ
Then why are you speaking to the intruder like you're friends?!
じゃあなぜ侵入者と親しくしゃべっている
We're not friends!
親しくねぇって
You can't trick me!
うそをついてもだまされんぞ
（邪魔…）
This is in the way.
うそなんかついてねぇ
We're not lying!
オレたちはただ
We're just...
うわ
There's... so much room here.
ここ　広い
Where am I?
どこ　ここ
Do I not have to dig anymore?
もう　掘らなくていいのか
Fire!
撃て
Bullets are ineffective?!
銃が効かんだと
Where... am I?
ここ　どこ
This is bad! He's headed for the development lair!
まずい　開発層に上がっていくぞ
After him!
追え
開発層に連絡を入れろ
Contact the men up there!
We need to go after him, too!
オレたちも追うぞ
うん
Right!
He's huge...
でかっ
It's... warm in here...
あったかい
Stay where you are!
動くな
Put out the fire.
消火
はっ
Roger!
当たったはずだが
I know I hit him...
It's no use, Boss!
ボス　だめです
Bullets don't work against him!
ヤツに銃のたぐいは効きません
What did you say?!
なんだと
All noncombatants are to withdraw immediately.
非戦闘員は即時退却
Shut off the alarm, too.
警報も止めろ
Don't let Drakma know about this commotion.
ドラクマのヤツらにここの騒動を悟らせるな
I've brought it, Boss!
ボス　持ってきやした
Has it been tested?
試運転は済んでいるのか
んなもんいらねぇですよ　開発班の自信作ですぜ
There's no need for that.
It's the proud of work of us developers!
Remove the fuse from the shell!
砲弾から信管を抜け
Aye, ma'am!
アイ　マム
第１弾　装填完了
First shell, loaded!
Fire!
撃て
直撃
Bull's eye!
Oww...
痛ぇ
It's a drag to feel pain, too...
痛いのも　めんどくせぇ
Don't just sit there!
ぼさっとするな　次弾装填
Load the next shell!
Fire!
撃て
Oww...
痛っ
Oh yeah, I forgot about my job.
そうだ　仕事
I have to dig.
穴　掘る
It's no use, General!
無理だ　将軍
He won't die no matter what!
あいつはいくら殺しても死なない
Won't die?!
死なない
What do you mean?!
どういうことだ
Why do you know so much about that thing?!
貴様　なぜあれのことを知ってる
I-I...
そっ　それは
I don't like dilly-dalliers!
とろくさいのは好かん
Answer everything that you can  answer!
私の質問　答えられるところだけ答えろ
How do you know about that thing?!
貴様　なぜあれのことを知っている
Are you a spy from Drakma?!
ドラクマの密偵か
No!
違う
Then is that thing a spy?!
ではあれは密偵か
I don't think so.
たぶん　違う
Does that thing know you?!
あれはお前を知っているか
Probably not.
たぶん知らない
What is  that thing?!
あれの正体はなんだ
I can't answer.
答えられない
Who is commanding him to act?!
あれは誰の命令で動いている
I can't answer!
答えられないんだ
なぜ答えられん
And why can't you answer?
Please try to realize...
察してくれ
This is my last question.
最後の質問だ
Do you two plan to ally yourselves with us?
貴様ら我々の味方をする気はあるのか
ここの人たちがやられるのは見たくない
I don't want to see the people here die.
Tell me what his body is made of.
あれの体がどうなってるか教えろ
I'm fairly certain his body structure and composition are identical to humans.
たぶん　体の構造や構成要素は人間と同じだ
人間と同じか
Identical to humans, huh...
バッカニア　戦車用の燃料を持ってこい
Buccaneer, bring me some tank fuel.
I'm going to pour it on him.
ヤツに浴びせる
Roger!
はっ
だからムダだ将軍
I'm telling you, it's useless!
Even if you light him on fire, he won't...
あいつは火をつけても簡単には
I've already gathered from the
previous attacks that he won't die.
殺せんのは先の攻撃でよく分かっている
ならば機能停止させてやるだけだ
In that case, I'll just shut off his bodily functions.
火炎よりもきついのをくらわせてやる
I'll let him have something far worse than flames.
I'll show you how we do things at Briggs.
ブリッグズ流を見せてやる
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
日本語字幕仕上げ：fayfay
ぶつかり合う肉体　さく裂する砲弾
The bodies that clash against each other..
The shells that explode in the air...
北の守りを脅かす　人造人間との大激戦
The battle against the Homunculus threatening the North defense.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
この戦いを制するのは我か　それとも
Will it be us who will win the battle? Or perhaps...
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第三十五話　この国のかたち
Episode 35, The Shape of This Country.
立ちふさがる者は排除する
All that stands in our way shall be annihilated.
それが北の掟
That is the law of the North.